<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>renanfernandes</title>
    <link>http://renanfernandes.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on renanfernandes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 11:32:06 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://renanfernandes.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure Arc Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/azure-arc-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 11:32:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/azure-arc-ubuntu/</guid>
      
        <description>Following the Wireguard series, I wanted to modernize my lab. one quick way to address that is to extend my two networks via Azure Arc so I can manage my resources more adequadely
Table of Contents Installing Azure CLI Creating the deployment script via Azure Arc Portal Running the onboarding script Installing Azure CLI The steps to install Azure CLI are pretty well described so I wont take time to do this.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pfSense and UDM-Pro, Happy together with Wiregard</title>
      <link>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/pfsense-udm-wiregard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 16:28:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/pfsense-udm-wiregard/</guid>
      
        <description>Now that Wireguard is officially supported by Ubiquiti, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided its time to fix my VPN once and for all. Since I have a pfSense up and running in Brazil and a UDM Pro here in US, I always leveraged a Site-to-Site VPN with ipsec to access my devices in both ends.
While my IPsec tunnel has been working fairly well over the years, now that Ubiquiti offers Wireguard support, its time for me to modernize my setup and look into some new use cases.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting your pfSense to Microsoft Sentinel</title>
      <link>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/sentinel-pfsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 14:55:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/sentinel-pfsense/</guid>
      
        <description>Just a collection of templates, scripts, configuration files and testing observations to make my life easier. This is part of my own GitHub repository (and one of the fews I make public), so use the content and scripts here at your own risk :)
Table of Contents Integrating Sentinel and Home Infrastructure Syslog server Provisioning the VM Configuring the Syslog Server Creating a Firewall rule to allow incoming traffic to Logstash Configuring pfSense Configuring Log Analytics Workspace Final Step: Sentinel!</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 11:05:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      
        <description>Hello World First post hello!</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>