<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>renanfernandes / renanm</title>
    <link>http://renanfernandes.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on renanfernandes / renanm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 09:08:40 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://renanfernandes.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure DNS</title>
      <link>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/azure-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 09:08:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/azure-dns/</guid>
      
        <description>I always used noip to manage my DNS Zones, but as I keep adding additional domains, it has become expensive. Azure charges only $0.50/month for the first 25 DNS zones, so thats a plus compared to $20+ I pay for NoIP. This guide shows how to create a zone and manage inside Azure.
Table of Contents Creating a new DNS Zone Creating a DNS record Creating CNAME record Final Steps Creating a new DNS Zone Seach for DNS Zones in the search bar and click on Create dns zone.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whoami</title>
      <link>http://renanfernandes.org/whoami/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 09:02:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://renanfernandes.org/whoami/</guid>
      
        <description></description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Arc Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/azure-arc-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 11:32:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/azure-arc-ubuntu/</guid>
      
        <description>Following the Wireguard series, I wanted to modernize my lab. one quick way to address that is to extend my two networks via Azure Arc so I can manage my resources more adequadely
Table of Contents Installing Azure CLI Creating the deployment script via Azure Arc Portal Running the onboarding script Installing Azure CLI The steps to install Azure CLI are pretty well described so I wont take time to do this.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pfSense and UDM-Pro, Happy together with Wiregard</title>
      <link>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/pfsense-udm-wiregard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 16:28:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/pfsense-udm-wiregard/</guid>
      
        <description>Now that Wireguard is officially supported by Ubiquiti, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided its time to fix my VPN once and for all. Since I have a pfSense up and running in Brazil and a UDM Pro here in US, I always leveraged a Site-to-Site VPN with ipsec to access my devices in both ends.
While my IPsec tunnel has been working fairly well over the years, now that Ubiquiti offers Wireguard support, its time for me to modernize my setup and look into some new use cases.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting your pfSense to Microsoft Sentinel</title>
      <link>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/sentinel-pfsense/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 14:55:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/sentinel-pfsense/</guid>
      
        <description>Just a collection of templates, scripts, configuration files and testing observations to make my life easier. This is part of my own GitHub repository (and one of the fews I make public), so use the content and scripts here at your own risk :)
Integrating Sentinel and Home Infrastructure As my home network continues to grow and more and more IoT devices are added, I felt the need to better improve my home security posture and frankly have a better visibilty over what is going on in my network.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://renanfernandes.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 14:16:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://renanfernandes.org/about/</guid>
      
        <description>Hugo, the world&#39;s fastest framework for building websites</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 11:05:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://renanfernandes.org/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      
        <description>Hello World First post hello!</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>